Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Newsletters and publications, 1947-2001 and undated RL.11681
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Newsletters and publications
1947-2001 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11681
10.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The London Office first opened in 1899. Collection includes client case histories, employee orientation and professional development manuals, office histories, newsletters, promotional materials, research reports, subject file periodicals and other printed materials. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The London Office first opened in 1899, and permanently in 1926.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Newsletters and publications were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. Corporate documentation
J. Walter Thompson Company. Newsletters collection
J. Walter Thompson Company. Publications
Collection Overview
Collection includes client case histories, employee orientation and professional development manuals, office histories, newsletters, promotional materials, research reports, subject file periodicals and other printed materials. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- Great Britain; Advertising -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising -- Research; Market research; Advertising agencies -- Management
- Newsletters and Publications, 1947-2001 and undated; 1
  - 1982-3 Reports, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - 40 Berkeley Square, 1967 (Box 12)
  - A Decade of Change, 1964 (Box 1)
  - A Glossary of Media Terms, 1993 (Box 1)
  - A History of Berkeley Square, 1977 (Box 1)
  - A Short Biography of Martin St. John O'Grady, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Account Plan, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Acorn: Direct Marketing, 1980/1983 (Box 1)
  - Advertising: Is this the sort of work that an honest man can take pride in?, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Advertising and sales promotion expenditure, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Advertising Expenditures in Western Europe 1960-1970, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Advertising Planning Methods, 1987; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Advertising Reports, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Advertising: An Annotated Bibliography, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Around the Piazza, 1986 (Box 1)
  - At the Receiving End, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Booklet No. 133, 1985-1988 (Box 1)
  - Bush House, Berlin, and Berkeley Square (George Butler), 1985 (Box 1)
  - Cable and Advertising in the Eighties, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Campaign Agency of the Year, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Challenges + Problems for International Advertising, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Children's Hour, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Colour Television--A Report, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Consumer Change in the Mid 70's, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Consumer Constraints, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Cooking and Recipe Usage in the 1970s (2 volumes), 1978; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Copying and Printing Services Kodak, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Crisis in Branding, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Daily Express parody Kinnett Hinks tribute, 1967 (Box 12)
  - Decimal Currency Board--Public Information Campaign, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Do you know your way around Europe?, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Drink News 1998 (1/2), 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Eating Behaviour + Attitudes to Food, Nutrition, and Health, 1981 (Box 1)
  - EMU News + Reports, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Ethiopian Endeavour, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Euro News, 1997-1998; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Euro News 1998, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Ferry News, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Financial Services Act 1986, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Focus On: Boots, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Focus On: Cars, 2000-2001; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Focus On: Cars, 2001; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Focus On: Charities, 1997-2001; 7 folders (Box 2)
  - Focus On: De Beers, 1998-2000; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Focus On: Drinks, 2000-2001; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Focus On: Ferries, 1998-2000; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Focus On: Financial Services, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Focus On: Gambling, 2000-2001; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Focus On: Healthcare, 2000-2001; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Focus On: Household Products, 2000-2001; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Focus On: Humour, 1999-2001; 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Focus On: Kids, 1999-2000; 7 folders (Box 4)
  - Focus On: Lifestyles, 2000-2001; 7 folders (Box 4)
  - Focus On: Luxury Goods, 2000-2001; 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Focus On: Media, 2000-2001; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Focus On: Media, 2001; 7 folders (Box 5)
  - Focus On: Nestle Rowntree, 1998-2001; 7 folders (Box 5)
  - Focus On: Retail, 2000; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Focus On: Retail, 2001; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Focus On: Rolex, 1998-2000; 7 folders (Box 6)
  - Focus On: Telecommunications, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Focus On: The RAF (Royal Air Force), 1997-2001; 8 folders (Box 5)
  - Focus On: Tobacco, 1998-2001; 8 folders (Box 6)
  - Focus On: Toiletries + Cosmetics, 2001; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Focus On: Toiletries + Cosmetics, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Focus On: Toy News, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Focus On: Toys, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Focus On: Travel, 2000-2001; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Food + Cooking in England, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Forecasting the Demand for Consumer Durables, 1964 (Box 7)
  - From Advertising to Sales, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Gallup Organization Poll, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Going Out, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Grocery Marketing: The Next Five Years, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Handbook of Early Advertising Art (Clarence Hornung), 1956 (Box 11)
  - Hanson Trust vs Imperial Group, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Having People In, 1981 (Box 7)
  - Hindustan Thompson: Media Overview, 1992 (Box 7)
  - HOME VIDEO, 1981 (Box 7)
  - How Advertising Works, 1974 (Box 7)
  - How Many Nations?, 1964 (Box 7)
  - How Much Do Television Commercials Cost To Make?, 1973 (Box 7)
  - How The Public Sees Banks, 1983 (Box 7)
  - How Useful is Proposition Testing?, undated (Box 7)
  - ICC International Code of Advertising Practice, 1987 (Box 7)
  - International Advertising: The Wheel Is Turning Full Circle, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Interpreting Public Attitudes--A Report by Mollie Tarrant, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Introduction to Impart, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Introduction to Media in the U.K., 1985 (Box 7)
  - Introduction to Media Research--U.K., 1985 (Box 7)
  - J. Walter Thompson Company Limited, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - J. Walter Thompson Identity Guidelines, undated (Box 7)
  - J. Walter Thompson News, 1967, 1985; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - J. Walter Thompson The Handbook, undated (Box 11)
  - J. Walter Thompson Year in View, 1998, 2000; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - J. Walter World, 1992 (Box 7)
  - John's Article in Guinness Time, undated (Box 7)
  - JWT, 1984 (Box 7)
  - JWT "T Square", undated (Box 8)
  - JWT Advertising, 1979 (Box 7)
  - JWT Advertising Agent, 1978 (Box 7)
  - JWT Brand Consultancy, 1994 (Box 7)
  - JWT Decimal Money Experiment, 1967 (Box 7)
  - JWT in Britain, 1970-1976; 7 folders (Box 7)
  - JWT in Britain in 1976: A Review of the Year's Advertising, 1977 (Box 7)
  - JWT in Britain in 1977: A Review of the Year's Advertising, 1978 (Box 7)
  - JWT in Close-Up, 1978, 1980; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - JWT in Europe, 1988 (Box 7)
  - JWT in Press and Posters, 1999-2000 (Box 7)
  - JWT in Print, undated (Box 11)
    Scope and Contents
    Part of a boxed series commemorating the 50th anniversary of JWT London at 40 Berkeley Square
  - JWT Knowledge, undated (Box 7)
  - JWT Lexicon + Wisdoms, 1987 (Box 7)
  - JWT London 1926-1966, 1967 (Box 7)
  - JWT London--Dates + Data, 1989 (Box 7)
  - JWT London Company Charts, 1977-1984; 6 folders (Box 7)
  - JWT Manchester: A Review of the Year's Advertising, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - JWT Media Person's Handbook, undated (Box 7)
  - JWT Performance Report, 1984 (Box 8)
  - JWT Red Book, 1899 (Box 8)
  - JWT Summary of services offered, 1947 (Box 11)
  - JWT World Identity Program, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Leveller, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Leveller, 1988; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Leveller articles, 1988; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Leveller comics, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Leveller drafts, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Leveller newspaper cuttings, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Leveller photos, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Leveller production cost, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Life Style Trends + Projections, 1987 (Box 8)
  - Lifestyle News, 1998 (Box 8)
  - Looking Forward to the Next 10 Years, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Market Modeling in Action, 1980-1986 (Box 8)
  - Market Research and the Retailer, undated (Box 8)
  - Market Research on a European Basis, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Marketing as a Career, undated (Box 8)
  - Media, T.V., + Repeat Fees, 1990-1991 (Box 8)
  - Mirror for a Lady, 1954 (Box 8)
  - Nottingham University--Decimalisation Study, 1972 (Box 8)
  - NUTS: U.K. Launch, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Old Men in Advertising, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Operational research + marketing, undated (Box 8)
  - Planning Guide, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Print Production Costs, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Private Label Received, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Procedures for Quality--Section 13: JWT Training Policy, 1992 (Box 8)
  - Procedures for Quality--Section 3: Account Management, 1992 (Box 8)
  - Professional Development Programme, 1998-1999 (Box 8)
  - Rascal Radio Planning Guide, 1981 (Box 8)
  - Read all about it!, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Regional Factors in T.V. Advertising, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Representatives' Basic Reading List, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Responses, Not Messages., 1995 (Box 11)
  - Retail Price Index, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Retailing in the Seventies, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Rise of T.V. Audiences, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Round the Square, 1952-1987; 15 folders (Box 8)
  - Round the Square, 1978-1985; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Round the Square--Relaunch, 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Social Change in Britain by 1984, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Statistics Explained: A Series of Essays, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Stena (ferry line) News, 1998 (Box 8)
  - Techniques in Market Forecasting, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Television Today and Television Tomorrow, 1983 (Box 8)
  - The ABC of JWT, 1995 (Box 11)
  - The Advertiser's Recipe Book, 1980 (Box 8)
  - The Andrex Story, undated (Box 8)
  - The British Codes of Advertising + Sales Promotion, 1995 (Box 8)
  - The Campaign with the Hole (Polo), undated (Box 11)
  - The Case for Advertising, 1976 (Box 8)
  - The Changing Face of Supermarket Shopping, 1964 (Box 9)
  - The Client/Agency Relationship, 1964 (Box 9)
  - The Consumer Has a Mind as Well as a Stomach, 1972 (Box 9)
  - The Fourth Stage Consumer: Planning Manifesto, 1993 (Box 9)
  - The Freeze-Drying Process, 1966 (Box 9)
  - The GEC bid for AEI (General Electric Company plc, Associated Electrical Industries), 1968 (Box 9)
  - The Gravity of Marketing, 1970 (Box 9)
  - The Great Outdoors, 1973 (Box 9)
  - The JWT Book of Surprises, 1995 (Box 11)
  - The JWT Decimal Money Experiment, 1967 (Box 9)
  - The JWT London Reading List, 1997 (Box 9)
  - The King Papers, 1988 (Box 9)
  - The Longer Lasting Agency, 1995 (Box 11)
  - The New Housewife (Tables and text), 1967; 4 folders (Box 9)
  - The New Housewife, 1973 v. 1965, 1975 (Box 9)
  - The New Wavelength, 1973 (Box 10)
  - "The presentation didn't go quite as we expected", 1972 (Box 10)
  - The Recession: Prospects for Consumer Goods, 1980 (Box 10)
  - The Regional City of Solent, 1965 (Box 10)
  - The Relationship between Purchasing Patterns and Advertising Exposure, 1971 (Box 10)
  - The Sales Curves of New Products, 1964 (Box 10)
  - The Thompson Way, 1989 (Box 10)
  - The T-Plan, 1964 (Box 10)
  - The Validity of Test Marketing, 1965 (Box 10)
  - The Visitors Book, 1982 (Box 10)
  - The Winner's Manual, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Three Myths about Our Export Trade, 1966 (Box 10)
  - Tomorrow's Food + Tomorrow's Consumer, 1971 (Box 10)
  - VIEWDATA, 1982 (Box 10)
  - West-Germany: A Lost Opportunity?, 1966 (Box 10)
  - What Do We Know About How Advertising Works?, 1967 (Box 10)
  - What is a Brand?, 1970 (Box 10)
  - What Puts the Prices Up?, 1965 (Box 10)
  - What Say the Augurers?, 1969 (Box 10)
  - What's Coming on Telly?, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Who Influences Whom?, 1968 (Box 10)
  - Will the Early Eighties be a Repeat of the Mid-Seventies?, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Women: The Moving Target in the U.K., 1986 (Box 10)
  - Women's Use of Media, 1975 (Box 10)
  - World-wide Opportunities for Better Living Standards, 1963 (Box 10)
  - WPP Group plc, 1987-1988 (Box 10)